# **MATTHEW MCKAY**

# **Software Developer**

**416-271-2613** 

matthewmckay@gmail.com

(7)

GitHub

0

Toronto, Ontario

B

matthewmckay.com

in

LinkedIn

#### WEB DEVELOPER PROFILE

Greetings! As a Software Developer, coding bootcamp and journalism grad, I bring experience in HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and React to the table as well as experience in back end languages like NodeJS/ExpressJS. My passion tech led me from owning/operating a construction company to a new, exciting career in web development. I now build responsive, accessible, and user-friendly applications in the virtual world, a transition eased by taking advantage of the skills I developed and refined from building in the physical world. I also place a huge emphasis on continuous learning and staying on top of emerging trends and technology in concert with strong communication, collaboration and prioritizing skills while working with clients and colleagues.

#### **SKILLS SUMMARY**

JavaScript | RESTful APIs & Firebase | Responsive Design | React | HTML5 | CSS/SASS/SCSS | Node.js Express.js | Git & GitHub | Web Accessibility | SEO | Technical Documentation | Paired Programming

Team Collaboration | Project Scope Management | Problem Solving | Critical Thinking | Communication

#### **HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS**

## Juno College - Project 4 - Quiz Game: What do YOU no? <Live><Repo>

React | FireBase | APIs | HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | JSX | Git | GitHub

- Collaborated with a group of developers and multiple third-party APIs to retrieve and manipulate object data to accomplish goal of creating quiz game requiring users to match homonyms with their definitions
- Wrote efficient, well-structured, and maintainable code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and front-end frameworks
- Demonstrated strong communication, collaboration, and prioritization skills while working with clients and colleagues

## Juno College - Project 3 - Rijks Museum Art Search < Live > < Repo>

React | APIs | HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | JSX | Git | GitHub

- Made multiple API calls using core React concepts to create a dynamic website allowing users to search, educate and get a
  close up look at world-renown art using different API endpoints from the world-famous Rijks Museum
- Participated in code reviews, provided constructive feedback, and continuously sought opportunities to improve skills and knowledge

#### Juno College - Project 2 - Horoscopes 4 U < Live > < Repo>

APIs | HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | SASS | Git | GitHub

- Displayed competency in working with third-party APIs, DOM manipulation, JavaScript, error handling and UI design, and proficiency in pair programming, coordination and communication
- Worked with UX and UI professionals to drive the user experience of web application
- Demonstrated ability to work effectively in a team environment

#### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

Juno College of Technology (formerly HackerYou) | Web Development Immersive Bootcamp Certificate | Toronto | 2022 University of Toronto | Hons. Bachelor of Science in Human Biology | Fine Art History Minor | Toronto Centennial College | Journalism Diploma | Toronto

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

General Contractor | DCD Construction | Self-Employed | Greater Toronto Area

Jan 2008 - Sep 2022

- As a business owner of own contracting business, managed complex projects, exceeded revenue goals year over year by over 50%, and provided excellent customer service to clients
- Worked with clients to manage their project expectations via daily timeline updates, revised designs and budgets, while demonstrating strong collaboration, problem-solving, multitasking, and critical-thinking skills to realize clients' goals
- · Designed, developed and implemented company's marketing plan through website, flyers and business cards
- · Used latest accounting software to stay updated on finances, identify areas of savings and maximize revenue and tax returns
- · Responded to and resolved emergency situations, including unexpected structural damage and flooding
- As an apprentice of DCD Construction, worked directly under general contractor in large residential and commercial projects providing clients with excellent customer service, communication and execution of 15-20 projects per year

**Volunteer** | Hennick Bridgepoint Hospital | Ambulatory Care Gym

May 2019 - Mar 2020

- · Helped physiotherapists rehabilitate knee replacement patients through set up, clean up, patient interaction in therapy gym
- Encouraged and motivated patients during their rehabilitation sessions. Assisted and escorted patients as needed

Public Address Announcer | University of Toronto | St. George Campus

Sep 2004 - Apr 2015

· Hosted hundreds of University of Toronto varsity-level hockey, volleyball, basketball, football and figure skating events